<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-03-25T20:26:07+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//</id><title type="html">Colm.io</title><subtitle>Colm Mulhall's personal blog about things that interest him.</subtitle><author><name>Colm Mulhall</name></author><entry><title type="html">iPad naming conventions</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/03/22/ipad-naming/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="iPad naming conventions" /><published>2017-03-22T08:40:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-22T08:40:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/22/ipad-naming</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/03/22/ipad-naming/">&lt;p&gt;Just like the iPhone, the iPad has never had naming conventions that have made much sense. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://512pixels.net/2017/03/on-that-new-ipad-2/&quot;&gt;latest release&lt;/a&gt; just further confuses things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPad&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPad 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The new iPad (with Retina display, 3rd generation)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The new iPad (with Retina display, 4th generation)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPad Air&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPad Air 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not confusing at all. And strangely seems to have just worked its way back to the original naming.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Colm Mulhall</name></author><category term="Apple" /><category term="ipad" /><category term="naming" /><summary type="html">Just like the iPhone, the iPad has never had naming conventions that have made much sense. The latest release just further confuses things:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Making Causality</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/03/13/making-causality/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Making Causality" /><published>2017-03-13T11:15:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-13T11:15:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/13/making-causality</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/03/13/making-causality/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/johnchidgey&quot;&gt;John Chidgey&lt;/a&gt; on making his podcast, &lt;a href=&quot;http://engineered.network/causality&quot;&gt;Causality&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Unsatisfied with the English translated section of the Amagasaki “accident” report I spent hours digging through the Japanese version of the sections relating to mental state of the driver bouncing between different translation tools to try and understand whether the driver had been getting enough sleep. Unable to locate a single definition source of information about Flint Michigan I went over dozens of articles on what lead up to the incident and dug through some textbooks on corrosion control techniques to understand what actually happened to the water supply. Unhappy with the popular documentary on BP Texas, I went through the multi-hundred page report and the Chemical Safety Board depiction of the event and stripped out the details that made the most sense as the root causes. That’s just three examples that come to mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had no idea such an amount of work goes into making these episodes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Colm Mulhall</name></author><category term="Podcast" /><category term="causality" /><summary type="html">John Chidgey on making his podcast, Causality:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Apple Pay Launches in Ireland</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/03/07/apple-pay-launches-ireland/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apple Pay Launches in Ireland" /><published>2017-03-07T12:40:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-07T12:40:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/07/apple-pay-launches-ireland</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/03/07/apple-pay-launches-ireland/">&lt;p&gt;Great to see it come to Ireland, but so far only supported by Ulster Bank and KBC.. 🙄&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Colm Mulhall</name></author><category term="Tech" /><category term="apple" /><category term="pay" /><summary type="html">Great to see it come to Ireland, but so far only supported by Ulster Bank and KBC.. 🙄</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Cases for (and Against) Apple Adopting USB-C on Future iPhones</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/03/02/lightning-to-usb-c/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Cases for (and Against) Apple Adopting USB-C on Future iPhones" /><published>2017-03-02T08:40:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-02T08:40:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/02/lightning-to-usb-c</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/03/02/lightning-to-usb-c/">&lt;p&gt;Federico Viticci on the potential move from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lightning_(connector)&quot;&gt;Lightning&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/USB-C&quot;&gt;USB-C&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;USB-C represents the dream of a single, small, reversible connector that works with every device, and it’s being adopted by the entire tech industry. USB-C isn’t as small as Lightning but it’s small enough. More importantly, it’d allow users to use one connector for everything; USB-A, while universal on desktop computers, never achieved ubiquity because it wasn’t suited for mobile devices. USB-C is.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Conversely, Lightning is under Apple’s control and Apple likes the idea of controlling their stack as much as possible (for many different reasons). A transition to USB-C would be costly for users in the short term, and it would be extremely perplexing the year after the iPhone 7 fully embraced Lightning.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Furthermore, unlike the transition from 30-pin to Lightning in 2012, Apple now has a richer, more lucrative ecosystem of accessories and devices based on Lightning, from AirPods and Apple Pencil to keyboards, mice, EarPods, game controllers, Siri remotes, and more. Moving away from Lightning means transitioning several product lines to a standard that Apple doesn’t own. It means additional inconsistency across the board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good summary from Federico Viticci about the arguments for and against moving to USB-C in the next iPhone. The arguments for moving are obvious, but the arguments against it are a bit more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s definitely more of an argument to be made for moving to USB-C than there was for ditching the headphone jack. It would also mean that the lifespan of the Lightning connector has been very short. There are plenty of people still using an iPhone 4/4S or iPad 2s - and those people will have completely missed the switch to Lightning.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Colm Mulhall</name></author><category term="Tech" /><category term="apple" /><category term="usb" /><summary type="html">Federico Viticci on the potential move from Lightning to USB-C:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">N.O.V.A. Legacy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/02/22/nova-legacy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="N.O.V.A. Legacy" /><published>2017-02-22T16:35:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-22T16:35:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/02/22/nova-legacy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/02/22/nova-legacy/">&lt;p&gt;Back in 2009, Gameloft released a first person shooter game on iOS called “&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/N.O.V.A._Near_Orbit_Vanguard_Alliance&quot;&gt;N.O.V.A. Near Orbit Vanguard Alliance&lt;/a&gt;”. This was as close as you could get to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Halo:_Combat_Evolved&quot;&gt;Halo&lt;/a&gt; on mobile, and for it’s time &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; it was a huge achievement in mobile gaming. It had an in depth story set across multiple maps, different weapons and enemies as well as local and online multiplayer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2017/2/nova1.png&quot; alt=&quot;NOVA&quot; class=&quot;image-single&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Avoiding snipers in &quot;The Mirror, The Ghost and The Gambit&quot;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gameloft followed up with two sequels for NOVA, as well as producing another great first person series alongside it, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Modern_Combat_(series)&quot;&gt;Modern Combat&lt;/a&gt;, which is more of a Call of Duty clone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gameloft have now &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gameloft.com/central/n-o-v-a/nova-story-retrospective-part-1/&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that they are releasing a remastered version of the original NOVA game, which will be free to play. This has sparked a debate over on AppSpy about the value in re-releasing mobile games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.appspy.com/feature/11158/the-monday-musing-is-nova-legacy-a-step-in-the-wrong-direction-for-mobile&quot;&gt;Harry Slater&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The question all of this raises is an interesting one is this really something we want to see on the App Store? Not just NOVA, but the whole concept of older games getting new leases of life. And I guess there are two standpoints.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;On the one hand the App Store is a flighty and changeable place. We’ve seen games disappear without trace, and thanks to Apple’s constant upgrading of iOS, there’s little chance that we’re ever going to get to play those games again.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;From that point of view, it’s good to see developers going back to games and refreshing them for a new era. Especially the likes of NOVA, which in its time was a resource-heavy AAA production, but now looks a little bit on the wonky side.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;But on the flip side of that, is this just another example of the creative malaise that’s sweeping through gaming as a whole. It’s not just another dude shooter, it’s a dude shooter that we’ve all already shot a whole bunch of dudes in before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To a certain extent I agree with this standpoint. I don’t see much value in re-releasing games that were only released a few years ago on iOS. What has worked really well, and I hope to see more of, is when console games get ported to mobile. Rockstar Games are making this biggest success of this with their &lt;a href=&quot;http://colm.io/2016/12/08/bully-coming-to-mobile/&quot;&gt;release&lt;/a&gt; of some console classics, most notably the Grand Theft Auto series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that’s where these kind of remasters make most sense - bringing them to mobile for the &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; time. Having said that, I can’t but be happy to see an App Store classic like NOVA being re-released in all its glory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Bearing in mind that this was still barely over a year into the life of the App Store, and iOS had only just learned the complex task of cut, copy and paste. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Colm Mulhall</name></author><category term="Games" /><category term="nova" /><category term="app" /><summary type="html">Back in 2009, Gameloft released a first person shooter game on iOS called “N.O.V.A. Near Orbit Vanguard Alliance”. This was as close as you could get to Halo on mobile, and for it’s time 1 it was a huge achievement in mobile gaming. It had an in depth story set across multiple maps, different weapons and enemies as well as local and online multiplayer.


  
    
      Bearing in mind that this was still barely over a year into the life of the App Store, and iOS had only just learned the complex task of cut, copy and paste. &amp;#8617;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Overcast 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/02/21/overcast3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Overcast 3" /><published>2017-02-21T09:03:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-21T09:03:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/02/21/overcast3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/02/21/overcast3/">&lt;p&gt;Marco Arment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Overcast 3 is now available, and it’s a huge update, mostly in the design and flow of the interface. I’ve been working on it since last summer, informed by over two years of testing, usage, and customer feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A massive update to my favourite podcast app.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Colm Mulhall</name></author><category term="Tech" /><category term="overcast" /><category term="app" /><summary type="html">Marco Arment:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">iPad and Mac—the early years</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/02/08/ipad-mac-early-years/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="iPad and Mac—the early years" /><published>2017-02-08T09:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-08T09:20:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/02/08/ipad-mac-early-years</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/02/08/ipad-mac-early-years/">&lt;p&gt;Dr Drang:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The biggest problem for the iPad is Apple’s unwillingness to let it become its own thing. Development of iOS is driven by the iPhone, which probably shouldn’t have the tools of a regular computer. But the iPad needs at least some of those tools if it’s to fulfill Apple’s promise to be a laptop replacement. Being yoked to the iPhone is holding it back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some good points by Dr Drang about the use of the iPad vs the Mac for getting work done. The single biggest thing holding the iPad back is software. The iPad has been around since 2010, and shipped with iOS 3. Fast forward to 2017, and the iPad has been though &lt;em&gt;seven&lt;/em&gt; major iOS releases. Of those, only one has brought real iPad-focused features - iOS 9.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s understandable that the iPhone has been taking priority over the iPad in terms of developing iOS, but it’s time for Apple to start making good of its promise that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1zPYW6Ipgok&quot;&gt;iPad is a replacement for the PC&lt;/a&gt;. It needs the basics - drag and drop, system wide multitasking, a better solution to the home screen, windows &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and a visible file system. Over reliance on the like of &lt;a href=&quot;https://workflow.is/&quot;&gt;Workflow&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://zapier.com/zapbook/iphone/&quot;&gt;Zapier&lt;/a&gt; just wont cut it for most people who want to make the transition from PC to tablet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As long as the iPad is treated as a fork of iOS to the iPhone, it’s never going to be become a PC replacement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;No, not Windows. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Colm Mulhall</name></author><category term="Tech" /><category term="apple" /><category term="ipad" /><summary type="html">Dr Drang:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Theatre Mode</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/02/01/theatre-mode/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Theatre Mode" /><published>2017-02-01T11:21:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-01T11:21:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/02/01/theatre-mode</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/02/01/theatre-mode/">&lt;p&gt;With WatchOS 3.2 it looks like Apple are introducing “Theatre Mode” to the Apple Watch. What this is, is basically a mode to put your watch on while at the cinema to mute notifications and avoid waking the screen automatically. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; There has been plenty of reports to suggest that Theatre Mode will be introduced on iOS this year too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it’s definitely a nice feature, even if a little bit niche &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, I hope that it isn’t Apples only attempt at a dark mode this year. I’ve long been anticipating a system wide dark mode on iOS, and Theatre Mode seems like a logical step towards it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t expect dark mode to show up in any of the iOS 10.3 builds over the next few weeks. If it’s to be introduced this year it will presumably be with iOS 11.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I think would be great would be to have the option to automatically enable dark mode at certain times of the day, similar to how you can enable &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macrumors.com/how-to/use-ios-9-3-night-shift-mode/&quot;&gt;Night Shift&lt;/a&gt; between certain times, or for it to be able to detect the level of light that you have and enable/disable based on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;9to5mac have published a good &lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5mac.com/2017/01/30/watchos-3-2-beta-1-theater-mode-video/&quot;&gt;overview&lt;/a&gt; of Theatre Mode on WatchOS with an accompanying video. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;And does it really warrant a place in Control Center? Surely this year will finally be the year that Apple allows us to customize the setting available to toggle in Control Center. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Colm Mulhall</name></author><category term="Tech" /><category term="ios" /><category term="dark mode" /><summary type="html">With WatchOS 3.2 it looks like Apple are introducing “Theatre Mode” to the Apple Watch. What this is, is basically a mode to put your watch on while at the cinema to mute notifications and avoid waking the screen automatically. 1 There has been plenty of reports to suggest that Theatre Mode will be introduced on iOS this year too.


  
    
      9to5mac have published a good overview of Theatre Mode on WatchOS with an accompanying video. &amp;#8617;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Micro.blog</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/01/18/microblogging/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Micro.blog" /><published>2017-01-18T08:57:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-18T08:57:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/01/18/microblogging</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/01/18/microblogging/">&lt;p&gt;Manton Reece is creating an interesting new social network based around blogging and owning your own content called “Micro.blog”. The idea is fairly simple - you can host your own blog right on Micro.blog, or you can simply use your RSS feed as an input, therefore keeping total control of your content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The great thing about this is that it can bring you a new audience and allow you to join conversations about other blogs all in one place. It’s like an RSS reader with social integration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big problem with social media is that you never truly own your content. Most services allow you to export your data at any time, so that in the event that the  platform shuts down you can hold onto your content. The great thing about Micro.blog is that you never have to give up any of your content in the first place, whether or not it lasts as a platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Judging by the support on the Micro.blog &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/manton/indie-microblogging-owning-your-short-form-writing&quot;&gt;Kickstarter page&lt;/a&gt;, we could be seeing it sooner rather than later.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Colm Mulhall</name></author><category term="Blogging" /><category term="micro" /><category term="blog" /><category term="kickstarter" /><summary type="html">Manton Reece is creating an interesting new social network based around blogging and owning your own content called “Micro.blog”. The idea is fairly simple - you can host your own blog right on Micro.blog, or you can simply use your RSS feed as an input, therefore keeping total control of your content.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Paul Kimmage meets Rory McIlroy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/01/10/rory-on-tiger/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Paul Kimmage meets Rory McIlroy" /><published>2017-01-10T11:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-10T11:01:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/01/10/rory-on-tiger</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/01/10/rory-on-tiger/">&lt;p&gt;Rory McIlroy on Tiger Woods:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m drawn to him, yeah. He’s an intriguing character because you could spend two hours in his company and see four different sides to him. When he’s comfortable and he trusts you — and his trust (sensitivity) is way (higher) than mine — he’s great. He’s thoughtful. He’s smart. He reads. He can’t sleep so that’s all he does — he reads stuff and educates himself on everything. But he struggles to sleep, which I think is an effect of overtraining, so I tell him to calm down sometimes. He’d be texting me at four o’clock in the morning: ‘Up lifting. What are you doing?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Colm Mulhall</name></author><category term="Sport" /><category term="golf" /><category term="tiger" /><summary type="html">Rory McIlroy on Tiger Woods:</summary></entry></feed>
