<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-10-23T00:09:47+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//</id><title type="html">Colm.io</title><subtitle>Colm Mulhall's personal blog about things that interest him.</subtitle><author><name>Colm Mulhall</name></author><entry><title type="html">iOS 11 is the buggiest release in years</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/10/21/ios-11-bugs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="iOS 11 is the buggiest release in years" /><published>2017-10-21T14:10:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-10-21T14:10:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/21/ios-11-bugs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/10/21/ios-11-bugs/">&lt;p&gt;Yoni Heisler, at BGR:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What’s unusual about iOS 11, though, is that it seems to be unusually and exceedingly buggy. While new iOS releases often have a few wrinkles to be ironed out, the problems users are seeing with iOS 11 are more pervasive and troubling than any iOS release in recent memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to agree with what’s being said here. iOS 11 has already gone through three minor releases since the official launch just over a month ago. That in itself is a sign that not all has gone to plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Battery issues have been widely reported. My iPhone 6S has never exactly had excellent battery life, but it’s getting slaughtered since updating to iOS 11. I’m seeing all sorts of strange bugs. Unresponsive home screen, apps quitting for no reason, Touch ID needing two takes, Mail stuck refreshing, and today’s bug: the clock has decided to disappear!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Colm Mulhall</name></author><category term="Apple" /><category term="iOS 11" /><category term="bugs" /><summary type="html">Yoni Heisler, at BGR:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">3D Touch app switcher will return</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/24/app-switcher-will-return/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="3D Touch app switcher will return" /><published>2017-09-24T22:10:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-09-24T22:10:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/24/app-switcher-will-return</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/24/app-switcher-will-return/">&lt;p&gt;Craig Federighi, replying to a mail about the removal of the 3D Touch app switcher gesture:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We regretfully had to temporarily drop support for this gesture due to a technical constraint. We will be bringing it back in an upcoming iOS 11.x update.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Thanks (and sorry for the inconvenience)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My only real complaint with iOS 11 was this. Looking forward to its return.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Colm Mulhall</name></author><category term="Apple" /><category term="gesture" /><category term="iOS" /><summary type="html">Craig Federighi, replying to a mail about the removal of the 3D Touch app switcher gesture:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">September event</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/18/september-event/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="September event" /><published>2017-09-18T09:45:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-09-18T09:45:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/18/september-event</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/18/september-event/">&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that we &lt;a href=&quot;http://colm.io/2017/09/09/leaks/&quot;&gt;knew the details&lt;/a&gt; of the majority of products that Apple were planning to announce, there is still a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; to talk about from Apple’s September event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple Watch enthusiasts finally got one of their most requested features - cellular data,  Apple TV enthusiasts (or whatever subset of them have a TV capable of driving 4K) got a nice - albeit minor - upgrade, and general Apple enthusiasts got to see the shiny new headquarters ‘Apple Park’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, I was most interested in seeing the new iPhones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2017/9/new-iphones.png&quot; alt=&quot;iPhone 8 Plus, iPhone X and iPhone 8&quot; class=&quot;image-single&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;iPhone 8 Plus, X and 8&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;iphone-88-plus&quot;&gt;iPhone 8/8 Plus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confusingly named ‘8’ and ‘8 Plus’ don’t let that fool you into thinking these are anything other than an iPhone ‘7s’ and ‘7s Plus’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first time since the iPhone 4S, the glass back returns and I’m glad it has. Aesthetics aside, this apparantly enables the 8’s to support wireless charging, which is something that I think will be great once it becomes widely supported in restaurants, airports and cars etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s great to see that the 8’s have got the same chip as the flagship iPhone X, the A11 ‘Bionic’, promising speeds up to 70% faster than the previous generation. The camera has also got it’s usual bump, and True Tone has been added to the display.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 8’s are both solid updates, even if they’re not the most exciting. Both phones are a great update for owners of iPhone 6s or older..and those who like to keep their phone prices below the thousand mark..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;iphone-x&quot;&gt;iPhone X&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iPhone X, pronounced ‘ten’ &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, is Apple’s first attempt at a bezel-less phone. There’s no denying that it looks great. Immediately all other iPhones look old in comparison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The notch at the top is what most people seem to be focusing on. For whatever reason, Apple decided to leave the notch at the top to accommodate the camera and sensors. They could have taken the option that Samsung took with the Galaxy S8 by having a thin bezel at the top and bottom of the phone where they can put any hardware they need without impacting on the screen. Until I use the phone in hand I can’t really criticize this design, but for now it does seem like a fairly big compromise for the bezel-less design. Unsurprisingly, the home button is also gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like the 8’s, the X has gotten the usual hardware updates like CPU bump, camera bump and notably an OLED display which should look great on a phone with a screen this big.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest change from a users perspective is probably the removal of Touch ID for Face ID, which again, will need to be tested in person before being judged. I love Touch ID on my 6s and it works quickly an flawlessly every time, so if Face ID doesn’t deliver the same user experience then it’s hard to see any benefit to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a bit torn on my opinion of this phone. I like the look of it, and I know that bezel-less is the way forward, but there’s no denying that this phone is a bit of a risk buy for most people. Ridiculous price aside &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, this is a first attempt from Apple with this design so it’s almost guaranteed to have problems. I wouldn’t recommend getting this phone unless you have a lot of money to spare, and are willing to accept compromises for a peek at the ‘future’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;An awful name in my opinion. What will next year’s iPhones be called?! &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;There’s almost no point in discussing high prices when it comes to Apple products at this point. This is a premium phone at an &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; premium price. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Colm Mulhall</name></author><category term="Apple" /><category term="iphone" /><category term="event" /><summary type="html">Despite the fact that we knew the details of the majority of products that Apple were planning to announce, there is still a lot to talk about from Apple’s September event.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Leaks</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/09/leaks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Leaks" /><published>2017-09-09T18:45:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-09-09T18:45:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/09/leaks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/09/09/leaks/">&lt;p&gt;There hasn’t been an Apple event with leaks this bad for as long as I can remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest leaks published on 9to5mac have all but confirmed the look, names and functionality of the new iPhones which are due to be announced this coming Tuesday at Apple Park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s most worrying from Apple’s perspective is that the majority of these leaks have come from Apple themselves, with their software being dug into by some talented people. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to admire the perseverance and skill of these guys in how they can dig into the software and paint a picture of what Apple are working on. But on the other hand it’s a shame to have all the excitement taken from the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, it’s up to Apple to ensure that any pre-release software is as bulletproof as possible, which is easier said than done when you have this level of interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/stroughtonsmith&quot;&gt;Steve Troughton-Smith’s&lt;/a&gt; Twitter is basically the Bible on leaks. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Colm Mulhall</name></author><category term="Apple" /><category term="leak" /><category term="event" /><summary type="html">There hasn’t been an Apple event with leaks this bad for as long as I can remember.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">iOS 11 release date</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/08/25/ios11-release-date/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="iOS 11 release date" /><published>2017-08-25T11:40:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-08-25T11:40:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/08/25/ios11-release-date</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/08/25/ios11-release-date/">&lt;p&gt;Historical iOS GM release dates:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;iOS Version&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Release Date&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;Day of the week&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;iPhone OS 1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;29th June 2007&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;Friday&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;iPhone OS 2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;11th July 2008&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;Friday&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;iPhone OS 3&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;17th June 2009&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;Wednesday&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;iOS 4&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;21th June 2010&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;Monday&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;iOS 5&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;12th October 2011&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;Wednesday&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;iOS 6&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;19th September 2012&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;Wednesday&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;iOS 7&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;18th September 2013&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;Wednesday&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;iOS 8&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;17th September 2014&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;Wednesday&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;iOS 9&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;16th September 2015&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;Wednesday&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;iOS 10&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;13th September 2016&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;Tuesday&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From iOS 5 onwards there is an obvious trend - midweek release in the third week of September. Based on that, and the move to Tuesday last year, I will go with &lt;strong&gt;Tuesday, September 12th&lt;/strong&gt; as the release date for iOS 11.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt; - I was a week off. iOS 11 releases to the public on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macstories.net/news/apple-announces-ios-11-to-launch-on-september-19th/&quot;&gt;19th September&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Colm Mulhall</name></author><category term="Apple" /><category term="ios" /><category term="release" /><summary type="html">Historical iOS GM release dates:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Apple discontinues the iPod nano and iPod shuffle</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/08/01/apple-discontinues-nano-shuffle/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apple discontinues the iPod nano and iPod shuffle" /><published>2017-08-01T11:10:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-08-01T11:10:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/08/01/apple-discontinues-nano-shuffle</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/08/01/apple-discontinues-nano-shuffle/">&lt;p&gt;Apple silently discontinued the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPod_Nano&quot;&gt;iPod nano&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPod_Shuffle&quot;&gt;iPod shuffle&lt;/a&gt; a few days ago. Although not entirely surprising &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; , it’s still worth noting the significance of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nano was, and still is an excellent device. I &lt;a href=&quot;http://colm.io/2016/01/18/ipod-nano-first-gen/&quot;&gt;still have&lt;/a&gt; a first generation one at home which despite being over eleven years old, wouldn’t look out of place today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shuffle is interesting in that it was the only music player in Apple’s lineup that was truly great for exercise. Until the Apple Watch fulfills a better role in health and fitness, there really isn’t any device now in the lineup that is portable and light enough to be comfortable to wear while running or in the gym.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The iPod touch hangs on as the last link to the iPod brand - but it’s unlikely to see any more significant updates as it slowly fades into history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all the nostalgia and admiration for these devices however, there is no getting away from the fact that the world has long moved on from the notion of syncing music to a device using a computer, and that is really what killed these iPods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The nano has not seen an update since 2012, while the last update to the shuffle dates back to 2010. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Colm Mulhall</name></author><category term="apple" /><category term="ipod" /><category term="nano" /><category term="shuffle" /><summary type="html">Apple silently discontinued the iPod nano and iPod shuffle a few days ago. Although not entirely surprising 1 , it’s still worth noting the significance of this.


  
    
      The nano has not seen an update since 2012, while the last update to the shuffle dates back to 2010. &amp;#8617;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How Apple created Nintendo’s best console</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/07/21/ios-gaming/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Apple created Nintendo’s best console" /><published>2017-07-21T15:55:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-07-21T15:55:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/07/21/ios-gaming</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/07/21/ios-gaming/">&lt;p&gt;Dan Masters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Apple has always had a rocky relationship with gaming. They have historically paid little attention to gaming — most notably on the Mac. However, post-iPhone they demonstrated an apparent newfound commitment to games by seemingly devoting significant resources and attention to it each year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;However, this would turn out to be a mirage, as they iterated very little and hardly encouraged developer adoption — instead taking the “Build it and they’ll come because we’re Apple” approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gaming is an area that Apple have gone backwards in on iOS. In the early days of the App Store, games were more ambitious and increasingly got more in line with console games. Compare that to today, where casual fremium games dominate the top grossing charts, and it’s clear to see that the App Store hasn’t become the thriving gaming platform to rival consoles that would be suggested all those years back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Game_Center&quot;&gt;Game Center&lt;/a&gt; is something that I was excited about when it was first released. The idea of having a rival to PSN and Xbox Live was on iOS showed that Apple were serious about iOS as a gaming platform. Save for one update, Game Center never got any real attention from Apple and it has slowly but surely slid into obscurity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iPhones and iPads have become real computing powerhouses. Imagine what a gaming company could produce if they could justify spending big money on a project for mobile platforms. I hope that the addition of &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/arkit/&quot;&gt;ARKit&lt;/a&gt; which was announced at WWDC, points towards a revival of gaming on iOS.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Colm Mulhall</name></author><category term="gaming" /><category term="apple" /><category term="nintendo" /><category term="game center" /><summary type="html">Dan Masters:

  Apple has always had a rocky relationship with gaming. They have historically paid little attention to gaming — most notably on the Mac. However, post-iPhone they demonstrated an apparent newfound commitment to games by seemingly devoting significant resources and attention to it each year.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A favorite hack</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/07/08/a-favorite-hack/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A favorite hack" /><published>2017-07-08T13:50:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-07-08T13:50:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/07/08/a-favorite-hack</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/07/08/a-favorite-hack/">&lt;p&gt;‘Underscore’ David Smith:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;First, the back story. During the introduction of iOS 7 one of the random side effects of the wide reaching changes to the iOS user interface was that app icon badges started to get truncated whenever they got above 4 digits long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;At first, I thought I’d have to remove the feature in iOS 7, until one fateful afternoon (while taking a shower, of course) I had the insight that I might be able to work around this. My realization was that the numbers were getting truncated based on their displayed width and not their digit count. Thus a number with a lot of 1s in it would not get truncated because the 1s are so thin, whereas a number with a lot of 4s in it would be truncated because they render much wider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cool little hack. There’s something comforting about knowing that even the most experienced developers sometimes use hacks like these to get their work done!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Colm Mulhall</name></author><category term="programming" /><category term="hack" /><summary type="html">‘Underscore’ David Smith:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">From Jekyll To Ghost</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/07/06/from-jekyll-to-ghost/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="From Jekyll To Ghost" /><published>2017-07-06T15:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-07-06T15:30:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/07/06/from-jekyll-to-ghost</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/07/06/from-jekyll-to-ghost/">&lt;p&gt;Roger Stringer, on his motivation for switching his blog from Jekyll to Ghost:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This blog tends to move engines every few years, WordPress, Second Crack, back to WordPress, over to Camel, then Jekyll and now nearly two years later, Ghost.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Ghost fits my current writing style, it’s markdown, and I can open it in any browser (or the desktop app) and just write, then publish.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;With Jekyll, I’d either write on GitHub, or use an app, or use write locally and then push to GitHub, which was fine, but not as smooth as I liked it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;After using Ghost to write heavily with Coded Geekery (my other slightly more opinionated blog), I just like that flow better, so I made the switch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always find it interesting to see other bloggers opinions on the technology that runs their sites. When I first created this site, I was actually following a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sitepoint.com/deploying-camel-js-blog-heroku/&quot;&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt; from Roger on how to set up a blog powered by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cliss/camel&quot;&gt;Camel&lt;/a&gt; and hosted on Heroku. Fast forward almost two years, and we have both moved on from &lt;a href=&quot;http://colm.io/2016/11/11/camel-to-jekyll/&quot;&gt;Camel to Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, and now Roger has changed once again to &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghost.org/&quot;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, Jekyll and GitHub Pages still fulfill any needs I have for this site, and I hope they will for a long time to come, but the beauty of self publishing is that the content is yours. The freedom of being able to move to any other technologies is great, and something that is sorely missed if you look to the like of Medium, Twitter, Facebook, or most other publishing platforms.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Colm Mulhall</name></author><category term="Blog" /><category term="jekyll" /><category term="ghost" /><summary type="html">Roger Stringer, on his motivation for switching his blog from Jekyll to Ghost:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">iPhone 10th anniversary round-up</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/06/30/iphone-turns-ten/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="iPhone 10th anniversary round-up" /><published>2017-06-30T17:17:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-06-30T17:17:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/06/30/iphone-turns-ten</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/06/30/iphone-turns-ten/">&lt;p&gt;Ten years ago yesterday, the iPhone first went on sale. It’s hard to believe it’s been that long, and even harder to think of a world without a smartphone in your pocket. Here’s some of the many write ups:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://daringfireball.net/2017/06/perfect_ten&quot;&gt;Perfect Ten&lt;/a&gt;” - Daring Fireball&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://sixcolors.com/post/2017/06/the-iphone-at-10-into-the-woods/&quot;&gt;The iPhone at 10: Into the woods&lt;/a&gt;” - Six Colors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://512pixels.net/2017/01/iphone-a-decades-worth-of-impact/&quot;&gt;iPhone: A Decade’s Worth of Impact&lt;/a&gt;” - 512 Pixels&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macsparky.com/blog/2017/6/10-years-with-iphone&quot;&gt;10 years with iPhone&lt;/a&gt;” - MacSparky&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5mac.com/2017/06/29/original-iphone-launch-and-reception/&quot;&gt;Happy 10th anniversary to the iPhone&lt;/a&gt;” - 9to5mac&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Colm Mulhall</name></author><category term="Apple" /><category term="iphone" /><category term="anniversary" /><summary type="html">Ten years ago yesterday, the iPhone first went on sale. It’s hard to believe it’s been that long, and even harder to think of a world without a smartphone in your pocket. Here’s some of the many write ups:</summary></entry></feed>
